## **MELANIE VILLELA**

Web Developer



2574 Marilee Lane Houston, Texas 77057



713-366-2532



melanienvillela@gmail.com



https://github.com/melanievillela



https://melanievillela.github.io/



• HTML5	• CSS3
• BOOTSTRAP	• MATERIALIZE
• FLEXBOX	<ul> <li>JQUERY</li> </ul>
JAVASCRIPT	• REACT
• NEXTJS	<ul><li>GATSBY</li></ul>
• NODE	• EXPRESS
• PHP	<ul><li>PYTHON</li></ul>
• FLASK	• HEROKU
• FIREBASE	<ul> <li>MONGODB</li> </ul>
• GIT	<ul><li>WEB SCRAPING</li></ul>
RESTFUL API	• UI/UX
• ILLUSTRATOR	<ul> <li>PHOTOSHOP</li> </ul>

# **EDUCATION**

University of Houston

Mechanical Engineering

2013

## ABOUT ME

Since 2007 I have been working in the oil and gas industry as a mechanical designer. I recently decided I needed a change so in January of 2017 I began the journey of learning front end web development. Since 2018 I have worked as a freelance web developer and in 2019 I began a contract position with a boutique web development company.



### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Web Developer 2019 - Current Colored Pixel Studios

Web Developer

2018 - Current

Freelance

Mechanical Designer

2013 - Current

Expro Group

Mechanical Drafter /

2007 - 2011

Documentation Specialist

Radoil



### **MAJOR PROJECTS**

#### DIMAS LANDSCAPING

Currently working on a landscaping website using React and Materialize. Creating a custom restful API for services available with pricing and implemented an online payment gateway via the Stripe API. Future updates will include an admin dashboard and scheduling module.

#### **BOLD BODY FITNESS**

Built and deployed a personal training website using React and Materialize. Created custom image galleries, contact forms and used React Router to transition between different pages.